A passion that cannot be denied. A betrayal that cannot be forgiven.
Revenge is a thriller, romance, drama film directed by Tony Scott.
Michael ‘Jay’ Cochran has just left the Navy after 12 years and he's not quite
sure what he's going to do, except that he knows he wants a holiday.
He decides to visit Tiburon Mendez, a powerful but shady Mexican
businessman who he once flew to Alaska for a hunting trip.
Arriving at the Mendez mansion in Mexico, he is immediately
surprised by the beauty and youth of Mendez’s wife, Miryea.
Michael J. Cochran, played by Kevin Costner.
Tiburon 'Tibey' Mendez, played by Anthony Quinn.
Miryea, played by Madeleine Stowe.
Amador, played by Miguel Ferrer.
Cesar, played by Tomas Milian.
Mauro, played by Joaquín Martínez.
Revenge is a 1990 American neo-noir romantic thriller film directed by Tony Scott and starring
Kevin Costner, Anthony Quinn, Madeleine Stowe, Miguel Ferrer and Sally Kirkland.
Some scenes were filmed in Mexico.
The film is a production of New World Pictures and Rastar
Films and was released by Columbia Pictures.
Revenge also features one of John Leguizamo's earliest film roles.
The film is based on a novella written by Jim Harrison,
published in Esquire magazine in 1979.
Harrison co-wrote the script for the film.
The film received a cult following since its release
especially for its dark theme and Scott's direction.
It was remade in Pakistan twice as Zid (1991) and Baghi (2001).
The film explores themes of mexico, revenge,
betrayal, revenge motive, revenge killing.
The tone is emotional and intense.